Francis D. Donovan Papers
© 2011 University of Connecticut
Francis D. Donovan Papers.
undated, 1829-1997.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Donovan, Francis D.
80 linear feet.
Francis D. Donovan (1917-2005) was a resident of Medway, Massachusetts, and an avid railroad photograph and memorabilia collector and researcher, particularly of materials associated with the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad and its predecessor lines. His papers consist of his writings and research files about the railroad; photographs of stations, engines, and railroad scenes; maps, scrapbooks, postcards and timetables.
MSS20060195
Biography
Francis D. Donovan was born in Norfolk, Massachusetts, on June 29, 1917. His love of railroads was fostered by his father, Daniel F. Donovan, a section foreman on the Wrentham branch of the Old Colony Division of the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad (better known as the New Haven Railroad). Although Daniel Donovan ended his employment with the railroad to become a policeman or security guard soon after his son was born, he retained his own interest in the railroad and friendships with railroad personnel, particularly with the legendary Gene Potter, engineer of the famous Ghost Train of the New York & New England Railroad.
Mr. Francis D. Donovan began working for the New Haven Railroad when he was fourteen, sweeping the floors of Switch Tower 232 in Walpole, Massachusetts. He became a tower operator when he turned eighteen and worked there until his left for his service in the United States Army during World War II. He was a tank sergeant in Europe and was awarded a Bronze Star for his heroic actions for gallantry under fire. When he came home in 1945 he decided that railroading was on its way out and became a sales representative for an industrial firm selling metal castings. In 1970, he became the Medway, Massachusetts, town clerk, retiring in 1990.
Mr. Donovan was an avid and lifelong collector, photographer and historian of the railroads of southern New England, particularly the New York & New England Railroad, a predecessor railroad line of the New Haven Railroad. He wrote several articles, including "Big Gene and the Ghost Train," in Yankees Under Steam (published in 1970 by Yankee Magazine) and "The East Thompson Train Wreck" in Danger, Disaster and Horrid Deeds (published in 1974 by Yankee Magazine). He was a national director of the Locomotive & Railway Historical Society and a member of many railroad societies, including the New Haven Railroad Historical and Technical Association.
Mr. Donovan had many other areas of interest and activity. As town clerk of Medway, Massachusetts, he resurrected the town historical society and wrote extensively about the town’s history. He served as the official Medway area climatologist and weather observer for the United States Weather Bureau. He was an amateur radio operator and an avid stamp collector. He had a passionate interest in the works of Samuel Johnson and amassed an extensive collection of Johnson’s writings. He repaired old clocks.
Francis D. Donovan married Mary Dowd in 1942 and they became residents of Medway, Massachusetts, in 1947. They had two children, Sheila and Kevin. He died at his home on December 9, 2005, at the age of 88.
Scope and Content
The Francis D. Donovan Papers consist of Mr. Donovan's writings and research files about the railroads, particularly those of New England; photographic images of stations, engines, and railroad scenes; maps, scrapbooks, postcards and timetables.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to New England railroads. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Donovan, Francis D.; Potter, Gene.
Organizations:
New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad.; New York & New England Railroad.
Subjects:
Locomotives.; Railroad stations -- New England.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Notebooks.; Publications.; Photographs.; Blueprints.; Maps.; Diaries.; Illustrations.; Manuscripts.; Typescripts.; Photocopies.; Notes.; Scrap-Books.; Sketches.; Drawings.; Obituaries.; Posters.; Newsletters.; Newspapers.; Histories.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The papers were donated by Mrs. Mary Donovan in the Spring of 2006.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series I: Papers, undated
  - Subseries A: Biographical and autobiographical information about Francis D. Donovan, undated (Box 74)
  - Subseries B: Correspondence, undated (Box 74)
  - Subseries C: General research files, undated (Box 74)
  - Subseries D: Timetables, undated (Box 74-79)
  - Subseries E: Postcards, undated (Box 103-108)
  - Subseries F: Ephemera, undated (Box 74)
- Series II: Subject files, undated
  - Files A-B (Box 80)
  - Boston & Maine Railroad record book (Box 93)
  - Files B-C (Box 81)
  - Files C-G (Box 82)
  - Files H-M (Box 83)
  - Files M-N (Box 84)
  - Files N (Box 85)
  - Files N-P (Box 86)
  - Files P-S (Box 87)
  - Steamboats (Box 93)
  - Files S-Z (Box 88)
- Series III: Scrapbooks, undated
  - (Box 89-93)
- Series IV: Maps, undated
  - (Box 94-96)
- Series V: Photograph files, undated
  - Files A-B (Box 97)
  - Files B-J (Box 98)
  - Files K-N (Box 99)
  - Files N (Box 100)
  - Files N-S (Box 101)
  - Files S-Z (Box 102)
- Series VI: Photographic materials, undated, 1829-1997
  - Subseries A: Prints, undated, 1829-1997
    - Sub-subseries 1: Stations, undated, 1858-1997
      - Sacramento, California, Southern Pacific Railroad station, circa 1925 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
      - Abington, Connecticut, railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 2)
      - Abington, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1938 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
      - Amsted, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
      - Andover, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 5)
      - Ansonia, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1910 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
      - Avon, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
      - Baltic, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1934 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
      - Bantam, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1932 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
      - Bantam, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1960 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
      - Barnard's, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
      - Beacon Falls, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1931 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
      - Berlin, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
      - Bethel, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
      - Bloomfield, Connecticut, Central New England Railway station, 1937 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
      - Bolton, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 16)
      - Branchville, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1966 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
      - Branchville, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
      - Branford, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
      - Brightwood, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 20)
      - Bristol, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 21)
      - Bristol, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 22)
      - Bristol, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 23)
      - Broad Brook, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 1:, Folder 24)
      - Broad Brook, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1966 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
      - Buckland, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1938 (Box 1:, Folder 26)
      - Buckland, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 27)
      - Buckland, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 28)
      - Burlington, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 1:, Folder 29)
      - Canaan, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1950 (Box 1:, Folder 31)
      - Cannondale, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 32)
      - Cannondale, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1966 (Box 1:, Folder 33)
      - Central Village, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 1:, Folder 34)
      - Central Village, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1935 (Box 1:, Folder 35)
      - Cheshire, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 1:, Folder 36)
      - Chester, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1935 (Box 1:, Folder 37)
      - Chesnut Hill, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 1:, Folder 38)
      - Chesnut Hill, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 1:, Folder 39)
      - Clark's Corner, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 40)
      - Clark's Corner, Connecticut, railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 41)
      - Clinton, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1939 (Box 1:, Folder 42)
      - Cobalt and Middle Haddam, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 1:, Folder 43)
      - Colchester, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1965 (Box 1:, Folder 44)
      - Colchester, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1965 (Box 1:, Folder 45)
      - Colchester, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 1:, Folder 46)
      - Collinsville, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1935 (Box 1:, Folder 47)
      - Connecticut River, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1935 (Box 1:, Folder 48)
      - Cornwall Bridge, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 49)
      - Cornwall Bridge, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 50)
      - Cornwall Bridge, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1948 (Box 1:, Folder 51)
      - Cromwell, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 52)
      - Cromwell, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 53)
      - Cromwell, Connecticut, railroad station, circa. 1890 (Box 1:, Folder 54)
      - Danbury, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 55)
      - Danielson, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 56)
      - Danielson, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1938 (Box 1:, Folder 57)
      - Danielson, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1935 (Box 1:, Folder 58)
      - Danielson, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 59)
      - Dayville, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1935 (Box 1:, Folder 60)
      - Dayville, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 1:, Folder 61)
      - Dayville, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 62)
      - Deep River, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 1:, Folder 63)
      - Deep River, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 64)
      - Derby, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 65)
      - Derby, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 66)
      - Derby, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 67)
      - Devon, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 1:, Folder 68)
      - East Berlin, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 1:, Folder 69)
      - East Canaan, Connecticut, Central New England Railway station, 1937 (Box 1:, Folder 70)
      - East Granby, Connecticut, Central New England Railway station, 1936 (Box 1:, Folder 71)
      - East Granby, Connecticut, Central New England Railway station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 72)
      - East Haddam and Moodus, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 1:, Folder 73)
      - East Hampton, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1965 (Box 1:, Folder 74)
      - East Hampton, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1965 (Box 1:, Folder 75)
      - East Hartford, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1928 (Box 1:, Folder 76)
      - East Haven, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1938 (Box 1:, Folder 77)
      - East River, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1935 (Box 1:, Folder 78)
      - East Thompson, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 79)
      - East Windsor, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 1:, Folder 80)
      - East Windsor, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 1:, Folder 81)
      - Ellington, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 82)
      - Elliot's, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 83)
      - Elliot's, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1938 (Box 1:, Folder 84)
      - Elliot's, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 85)
      - Elliot's, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 86)
      - Elmwood, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 1:, Folder 87)
      - Enfield Bridge, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 1:, Folder 88)
      - Essex, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1935 (Box 1:, Folder 89)
      - Fairfield, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1940 (Box 1:, Folder 90)
      - Falls Village, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1949 (Box 1:, Folder 91)
      - Falls Village, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 1:, Folder 92)
      - Falls Village, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 93)
      - Farmington, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 1:, Folder 94)
      - Fairhaven, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 95)
      - Florence, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 96)
      - Gales Ferry, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 97)
      - Gales Ferry, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 98)
      - Gaylordsville, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 99)
      - Georgetown, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 1:, Folder 100)
      - Georgetown, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1946 (Box 1:, Folder 101)
      - Granby, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1949 (Box 1:, Folder 102)
      - Granby, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1967 (Box 2:, Folder 103)
      - Granby, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1967 (Box 2:, Folder 104)
      - Granby, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 2:, Folder 105)
      - Greenville, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 106)
      - Griffin's, Connecticut, Central New England Railway station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 107)
      - Grosvenordale, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 108)
      - Grosvenordale, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 109)
      - Groton, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1917 (Box 2:, Folder 110)
      - Grove Beach, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1972 (Box 2:, Folder 111)
      - Grove Beach, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1908 (Box 2:, Folder 112)
      - Guilford, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 2:, Folder 113)
      - Haddam, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 114)
      - Hadlyme, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 115)
      - Hampton, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 116)
      - Hampton, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 117)
      - Hawleyville, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 118)
      - Hayden's, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 2:, Folder 119)
      - Hazardville, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1962 (Box 2:, Folder 120)
      - Hazardville, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 121)
      - Hop River, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 122)
      - Hoskins, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 2:, Folder 123)
      - Jewett City, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 124)
      - Kent, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1956 (Box 2:, Folder 125)
      - Kent, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1956 (Box 2:, Folder 126)
      - Kent, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 127)
      - Lake, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1935 (Box 2:, Folder 128)
      - Lakeville, Connecticut, Central New England Railway station, 1958 (Box 2:, Folder 129)
      - Leete's Island, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1935 (Box 2:, Folder 130)
      - Lime Rock, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 131)
      - Litchfield, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 2:, Folder 132)
      - Litchfield, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1960 (Box 2:, Folder 133)
      - Lyme and Black Hall, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1935 (Box 2:, Folder 134)
      - Madison, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1939 (Box 2:, Folder 135)
      - Manchester, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 136)
      - Mansfield, Connecticut, Central Vermont Railroad station, 1966 (Box 2:, Folder 137)
      - Melrose, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1934 (Box 2:, Folder 138)
      - Melrose, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 139)
      - Meriden, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 140)
      - Meriden, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 141)
      - Middlefield, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 142)
      - Middlefield Center, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 143)
      - Middletown, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 144)
      - Middletown, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 145)
      - Midway, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 146)
      - Milford, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 2:, Folder 147)
      - Milldale, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 2:, Folder 148)
      - Millstone, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 149)
      - Moosup, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 2:, Folder 150)
      - Moosup, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 151)
      - Morris, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1932 (Box 2:, Folder 152)
      - Mount Carmel, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1938 (Box 2:, Folder 153)
      - Mystic, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 2:, Folder 154)
      - Mystic, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1966 (Box 2:, Folder 155)
      - New Haven, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1917 (Box 2:, Folder 156)
      - New Haven, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1888 (Box 2:, Folder 157)
      - New London, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1910 (Box 2:, Folder 159)
      - New Milford, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1964 (Box 2:, Folder 160)
      - New Milford, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1934 (Box 2:, Folder 161)
      - New Milford, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1956 (Box 2:, Folder 162)
      - New Preston, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 2:, Folder 163)
      - Newington, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 158)
      - Newtown, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1931 (Box 2:, Folder 164)
      - Newtown, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 165)
      - Newtown, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1946 (Box 2:, Folder 166)
      - Noank, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 167)
      - North Cromwell, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 168)
      - North Grosvenordale, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1939 (Box 2:, Folder 170)
      - North Haven, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 171)
      - North Haven, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1960 (Box 2:, Folder 172)
      - North Windham, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 173)
      - Northford, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 169)
      - Norwich, Connecticut, Central Vermont Railroad Station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 174)
      - Norwich, Connecticut, Central Vermont Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 175)
      - Norwich, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1885 (Box 2:, Folder 176)
      - Norwich, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1911 (Box 2:, Folder 177)
      - Norwich, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1911 (Box 2:, Folder 178)
      - Norwich, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 2:, Folder 179)
      - Norwich, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, circa 1950 (Box 2:, Folder 180)
      - Oakville, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1961 (Box 2:, Folder 181)
      - Oneco, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 182)
      - Oneco, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1938 (Box 2:, Folder 183)
      - Ore Hill, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 184)
      - Plainfield, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 2:, Folder 185)
      - Plainfield, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 2:, Folder 186)
      - Plainville, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1955 (Box 2:, Folder 187)
      - Plainville, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 188)
      - Plantsville, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 2:, Folder 189)
      - Pomfret, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1992 (Box 2:, Folder 190)
      - Pomfret, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1992 (Box 2:, Folder 191)
      - Pomfret, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1992 (Box 2:, Folder 192)
      - Portland, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, circa 1930 (Box 2:, Folder 193)
      - Putnam, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 194)
      - Putnam, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1888 (Box 2:, Folder 195)
      - Putnam, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1935 (Box 2:, Folder 196)
      - Putnam, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1992 (Box 2:, Folder 197)
      - Redding, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1946 (Box 2:, Folder 198)
      - Rockfall, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 199)
      - Rockville, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1935 (Box 2:, Folder 200)
      - Rockville, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1938 (Box 2:, Folder 201)
      - Rocky Hill, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, undated (Box 2:, Folder 202)
      - Rocky Hill, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1973 (Box 2:, Folder 203)
      - Rocky Hill, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 204)
      - Romford, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 205)
      - Sandy Hook, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, circa 1920 (Box 3:, Folder 206)
      - Saybrook, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1936 (Box 3:, Folder 207)
      - Saybrook, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1935 (Box 3:, Folder 208)
      - Saybrook Junction, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 3:, Folder 209)
      - Saybrook Point, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, circa 1936 (Box 3:, Folder 210)
      - Scotland, Connecticut, New Haven Railroad station, 1937 (Box 3:, Folder 211)